

# Corin W.G. Baird

# Personal Biography

A motivated and enthusiastic online evangelist, with many hats, who is a passionate consumer of all things web. Having worked online for 19 years, in healthcare for a total of 9, on market leading websites and with major brands, a broad knowledge base and innovative commercial sense has been developed.

A committed, target driven social listener with strong delivery and interpersonal skills.

#### **Employment**

April 2019 – Present VMLYRx (Formerly Sudler)

# **Head of Digital**

- Initially the sole digital driving force in the agency, working across all internal and client teams (Diabetes, Cardiovascular, Oncology, Haemophilia) and creative department, bringing onboard UX expertise and training existing colleagues as digital experts.
- Member of the strategy team, working across all brands, identifying behaviours, beliefs and unmet needs of our target customers that the agencies team will use within any of the briefs/campaigns. Researching digitally as well as first hand interviews with specialists/target audience. Campaigns ranging from £75k to £5M.
- Educator both within the agency and for clients. Teaching teams about digital, bringing
  in new tech partners as well as implementing smoother agile processes where possible
  and updating existing ones to include digital as the lead deliverable and implement
  success metrics as a standard offering. Attending client sales rep training days,
  bringing to life the new aspects of technology they can use and introducing new
  Covid19 non-personal/remote alternatives. (Increasing agency revenue as a result)
- Key role in delivering successful new business pitches bringing in clients to the agency
- Lead £2M Breast cancer patient awareness project, grown from simple print, UK only, to a global digital campaign, including video shoot and website. Nominated for 3 awards. www.whatsbreastforme.co.uk
- Completed a new HCP site launch for rare blood cancers as revenue stream for existing client. From strategy, concept, build and delivery in record time for client and agency. Success in the UK led to full EMEA roll out.

November 2015 - March 2019 Nitro Digital

# **Content and Experience Director - Group Account Director**

- Lead the development of the agency's digital content, editorial, video and VR, for pharmaceutical clients ranging from IBD, Oncology to Cardiovascular and also animal health. Bringing the social and commercial digital content techniques to a more regulated environment.
- Product lead for global thrombosis product, multilingual site redesign, for 6 HCP audiences as well as patients and carers, €3M p/a budget. In addition to this, including product launch, congress coverage and further indications. Developing business into 2 other teams within the client brand portfolio.
- A research first mentality with process including strategy thru concept and design to delivery and ongoing maintenance.
- Lead creativity with partnership pitches for new business
- Nose to tail project management of some complicated project as well as a leadership role across internal teams.
- Key relationship with senior client team and understanding of their goals and translating into strategic KPIs for all deliverables.

April 2015 – October 2015 BuzzFeed UK

# **Head of Creative Content EU**

- Leading the Creative Team of 6 in producing relevant, shareable social content with business partners for BuzzFeed UK and EU, including native content, custom development and video
- Lead knowledge based sessions for clients and agencies on the story of how BuzzFeed works and succeeds
- Use my expertise to provide guidance and solutions to Creatives
- Lead all 100k+ deals from a creative and strategic standpoint, delivering programs ranging from \$50k to \$1mill
- Attend client and agency meetings with brand strategy and brand relationship managers and recommend the best mix of paid, earned and owned media.
- Work closely with SMT to implement new processes

- Interface with US Creative team to introduce new products in UK market and new markets in Europe
- Evaluate all pre-sale ideas and ensure the concepts represent both the brand and in a
  way that fits within the BuzzFeed content model.
- Delivering on record targets for the last 3 quarters.

#### June 2013 – March 2015 Sizmek – Formerly MediaMind

## **Head of Creative Production EMEA**

- Head creative agency within the business, responsible for all creative output for the EMEA region.
- Projects ranging from simple conversion of creative, to full nose to tail campaigns, from concept through strategy and planning, design to delivery, project managing every step. Ranging from £2k to £500k campaigns. Championing creativity and strategic design in response to digital briefs
- Maintain cost effectiveness and profitability, be they ad hoc or within realms of contracts with partners.
- With a US colleague, set up and staff up a creative development team in the Philippines.

# May 2012 – May2013 The Independent and The Evening Standard London

# **Head of Digital Creative Strategy**

- Lead the team responsible for all digital creative output, outside display, across the
  portfolio, manage P&L for all campaigns, as well as quality control, the teams training
  needs and resourcing.
- Collaborate with print teams to devise innovative cross media solutions using all tools possible, such as TGI, Omniture and Mintel data.
- Ensure digital and print teams are aware and fully trained on all aspects of the online media offering including social, mobile and tablet capabilities and develop sales collateral for proposals ad hoc as well as from editorial calendar.
- Develop and implement strategy for the department to ensure revenue growth in order to make sure targets are met.

## December 2008 – March 2012 AOL UK and Huff Post UK London

# **Creative Solutions** (initially business development)

- Creative solutions lead for agency sales teams in the UK and Europe. Voted no.1 for creativity and service in IPA survey
- Concept, design, plan and deliver market leading partnership opportunities at a profit, across our brands as well as working with the editorial team on recommendations regarding content and tools that would help increase advertising revenues.
- Find new creative formats to use across the sites and network from the rich media vendors and creative agencies
- Identifying strategic opportunities, potential advertising partners & key ad revenue generating areas to help drive and shape the future direction of AOL Properties and our Network Partners.

# April 2008 – Oct 2008 All Digital Downloads

### London

#### **Product Director**

- Manage all of the user side focus of the new Web 2.0 Entertainment site, including music and video store, editorial content and full social network.
- Bring on board various technical partners that are needed for new sites, including ad servers, site statistics as well as commissioning out creative technical applications such as widgets for other social networks.
- Being part of the senior management team, deciding on the direction of the site, ad strategy, commercial partners, amount of commercial integration, marketing strategy and PR, as well as being involved in various label relationships.

#### Dec 2005 – April 2008 Hearst Digital formerly Handbag Publishing GroupLondon

#### **Head of Client Services**

- Manage and oversee all aspects of the creative/production team including project scheduling & resource allocation, and introduced a new company wide Project Management process backed by senior management, digitally and press. Increasing service levels, delivery and cost efficiency dramatically.
- Conceive and develop excellent creative concepts for one large cross media project for a blue chip confectionary client, the online idea became the larger part of the cross media offering and took 2/3 or the overall revenue. Originally it was ¼ of budget..
- Manage the larger client direct campaigns that run across the Network, namely the L'Oreal Brands. P&G, Unilever, Nestlé, Kraft, BAA and large agencies, especially those under the Group M umbrella and Starcom.

# Aug 2003- Dec 2005 Guardian Newspapers Ltd London

#### **Campaign Manager, Guardian Unlimited**

- Sole campaign manager for complete Commercial (London/Manchester), Classified and Sponsorship teams
- Adviser and trainer for colleagues on roll out of new adserver, from Netgravity to Doubleclick Adserver5.

#### Feb 2002- Aug 2003 Lycos UK

London

### **Account Manager, Operations Team**

- Manage the implementation through to the final reporting of the campaign and remain the primary point of contact throughout this process, using Double Click Adserver and Adinsight
- Account manage major blue chip campaigns including, BT, Vodafone, BA, COI, BMG, Renault, Zurich, and Buena Vista. As Well as agencies including I-level, Carat, OMD, Zenith.

Nov 2001- Feb 2002 Big Picture

London

#### **Field Marketing Training Consultant**

- Initially joined the company on a temporary basis, but was given permanent contract to set up and manage the training programme for the field marketers working on consumer electronic products for in-store demonstration purposes
- The programme included general training as well as focusing on presentation skills and audit procedures

Nov 2000 - Sep 2001 24/7 Media

London

# Campaign Manager (initially: Ad operation co-ordinator)

- Started in the technical department, programming the advertising to various sites in the portfolio, gaining knowledge of the new media market. Use of Adforce and 24/7 Connect Ad Servers
- Duties involved, reporting, optimisation of campaigns, (approx 120/wk) recommending retargeting to a more appropriate audience, monitoring delivery, answering technical queries from agencies, collecting creatives offering advice

Apr 2000 – Oct 2000 Centaur Communications

London

Southampton,

# **Classified Sales Executive**

 Worked on Design Week, one of Centaur's flagship titles as well as the re-launch of a number of trade areas within the publication

#### Education

1996 - 2000 MSc Human Sciences (chiropractic)
Anglo-European College of Chiropractic

Bournemouth, Dorset

1995 - 1996 Southampton University

Hants

1989 - 1995

Canford School

Wimborne. Dorset

A Levels: Biology, Chemistry, Physics

GCSEs: 8 A's, 2 B's, 2 C's.

# References A

Available on request

# Languages

Fair to good communication and written French and Spanish

## Interests

A bit of a travel bug. A culture vulture ranging from theatre to art, along with general sports and health pursuits